Guide to the Pennsylvania Association for Retarded Children, Allegheny County Chapter Records, 1952-1965 AIS.1966.01
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Pennsylvania Association for Retarded Children, Allegheny County Chapter Records
1952-1965
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Pennsylvania Association for Retarded Children. Allegheny County Chapter
AIS.1966.01
23.43 Linear Feet (34 boxes)
This collection contains the records of the Pennsylvania Association for Retarded Children, Allegheny County Chapter. This chapter's purpose was to tend to the general welfare of mentally retarded children in Pittsburgh and Allegheny County. The association had interest in school policies as well as home care and further education of the mentally retarded, sponsoring socialization classes to help prepare children for the world. The chapter changed its name to Arc of Allegheny in the 1980s. This collection contains administrative information, journals, meeting minutes, correspondence, articles, committee data, as well as information on social events.
History
The Allegheny County Chapter of the Pennsylvania Association for Retarded Children (PARC) was a voluntary, non-profit organization formed in 1950. The chapter was founded by a group of families with children affected by mental retardation. The group was originally named Friends of the Mentally Retarded. It wasn't until 1956 that Friends of the Mentally Retarded became a local chapter of PARC, renaming itself the Allegheny County Chapter of the Pennsylvania Association for Retarded Children.
The goal of the chapter was to promote the general welfare of mentally retarded children of all ages in western Pennsylvania, regardless of race, color or creed. This was done in communities, institutions both public and private, and religious schools. PARC also sought to further the advancement of research and therapy in the field of mental retardation. The chapter was responsible for creating a better understanding of the problems associated with mentally retarded children by reaching out to the public.
The chapter elected its first officers in May, 1951 although it actually began with temporary officers in the fall of 1950. By the mid 1950s, the chapter had developed services such as sheltered workshops, camping opportunities and day classes established in the Pittsburgh Board of Education, the Allegheny County School System, and the Catholic Diocesan Schools. These classes gave children the opportunity for further education in a safe environment. Swimming classes and summer camp activities were created for families and their children at the Brashear Association Camp and the David B. Oliver Pool. PARC also initiated the first teacher-training program in Pennsylvania for the education of mentally retarded children. PARC changed its name to Association of Retarded Children (ARC) of Allegheny County in the 1980s. This organization is still in operation to date.
Scope and Content
This collection reflects the activities of the Pennsylvania Association for Retarded Children, Allegheny Chapter from 1952-1963. It includes administrative records, correspondence, meeting minutes, information on social events, articles, fundraising information, and data on PARC and National Association for Retarded Children (NARC).
Arrangement
The collection has been divided into the following series:
Series I. Administrative Records, 1952-1964
Series II. Correspondence, 1953-1963
Series III. Subject and Program Files, 1953-1963
Series IV. Committees, 1953-1963
Series V. Employment and Membership, 1959-1963
Series VI. Publicity, 1956-1963
Series VII. Social Events, 1958-1963
Series VIII. Conventions, 1956-1960
Series IX. Fundraising, 1953-1961
Series X. Programs, 1953-1963
Series XI. Scholarships and Awards, 1955-1956
Series XII. Articles, 1954-1964
Series XIII. Miscellaneous Material, 1958-1960 and undated
Series XIV. PARC/NARC, 1952-1963
Additional scope and content notes are found at each series level.
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Acquisition Information
These records were a gift of the Pennsylvania Association for Retarded Children, January 10, 1966.
Previous Citation
Pennsylvania Association for Retarded Children, Allegheny County Chapter Records, AIS.1966.01, Archives Service Center, University of Pittsburgh
Associations; Theaters -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Amusements -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Collective labor agreements -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Mentally handicapped children -- Pennsylvania -- Allegheny County; Mentally handicapped children -- Education -- Pennsylvania -- Allegheny County; Health and Welfare Association of Allegheny County; National Association for Retarded Children; Pennsylvania Association for Retarded Children
- Administrative Records, 1952-1964; I.
  Scope and Content Notes
  This series contains administrative records, the constitution and by-laws as well as information on the president and treasurer, budget data, correspondence, payroll registers, journals and meeting minutes.
  - Constitution, By-laws; Institutions Committee, November, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Constitution and By-laws, 1958-1961 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - First Draft of a Revised Constitution, Unofficial and Unedited, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Constitution and By-law (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - President's File, 1954-1959 (Box 1, Folder 5-8)
  - Correspondence, Treasurer, 1954-1958 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Daybook (Receipts and Disbursements), Treasurer, 1952-1957 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Cash receipts, Treasurer, 1954-1964 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Disbursements, Treasurer, 1958-1964 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Miscellaneous, Treasurer, undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Report of Income and Disbursements, Treasurer, 1953-1963 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Audit, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Annual Budget Requests, 1958-1959 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Budgets Book, 1960-1961 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Budget, 1958-1959 (Box 2, Folder 3-8)
  - Budget Contributions (Box 2, Folder 9-10)
  - Proposed Budget (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Payroll Register, 1957-1960 (Box 3, Folder 1-4)
  - Journal (blank) (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Journal, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Journal, 1957-1959 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Payment Notebook, 1956-1958 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Board of Directors, May, 1960 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Board Meetings, 1955-1956 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Board Minutes, 1961-1965 (Box 4, Folder 3-6)
  - Board of Directors, and, 1962 1965 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Executive Director's Reports, 1957-1958 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Executive Director, 1957 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Functions and Duties of Boards (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - General Meetings - Minutes, 1960-1962 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - General Meetings ACCPARC (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Record Secretary's File, 1954-1955 (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Correspondence, 1953-1963; II.
  This series contains correspondence to and from PARC from 1953-1963. It has been arranged alphabetically and chronologically.
  - Corresondence, Alphabetical, 1.
    - A, Correspondence, 1959-1963 (Box 5, Folder 1-2)
    - B, Correspondence, 1959-1963 (Box 5, Folder 3-4)
    - C, Correspondence, 1959-1963 (Box 5, Folder 5-6)
    - D, Correspondence, 1959-1963 (Box 5, Folder 7-8)
    - E, Correspondence, 1959-1963 (Box 5, Folder 9-10)
    - F, Correspondence, 1959-1963 (Box 5, Folder 11-12)
    - G, Correspondence, 1959-1963 (Box 5, Folder 13-14)
    - H, Correspondence, 1959-1963 (Box 5, Folder 15-16)
    - I, Correspondence, 1959-1963 (Box 5, Folder 17-18)
    - J, Correspondence, 1959-1963 (Box 5, Folder 19-20)
    - K, Correspondence, 1959-1963 (Box 5, Folder 21-22)
    - L, Correspondence, 1959-1963 (Box 6, Folder 1-2)
    - M, Correspondence, 1959-1963 (Box 6, Folder 3-5)
    - Mc, Correspondence, 1959-1963 (Box 6, Folder 6-7)
    - N, Correspondence, 1963 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - O, Correspondence, 1963 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - P, Correspondence, 1961-1963 (Box 6, Folder 10-11)
    - R, Correspondence, 1962-1963 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - S, Correspondence, 1962-1963 (Box 6, Folder 13-14)
    - T, Correspondence, 1962-1963 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - U, Correspondence, 1962-1963 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - V, Correspondence, 1961-1963 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - W, Correspondence, 1962-1963 (Box 6, Folder 18-19)
    - X,Y, and Z, Correspondence, 1963 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Copies of Correspondence, by month, 2.
    - Copies of Correspondence, August, 1957 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Copies of Correspondence, September, 1957 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Copies of Correspondence, October, 1957 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Copies of Correspondence, November, 1957 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Copies of Correspondence, December, 1957 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Copies of Correspondence, January, 1958 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Copies of Correspondence, February, 1958 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Copies of Correspondence, March, 1958 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Copies of Correspondence, April, 1958 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Copies of Correspondence, May, 1958 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Copies of Correspondence, June, 1958 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Copies of Correspondence, July, 1958 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Copies of Correspondence, August, 1958 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Copies of Correspondence, September, 1958 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Copies of Correspondence, October, 1958 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Copies of Correspondence, November, 1958 (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Copies of Correspondence, December, 1958 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence, General, 3.
    - Correspondence with National Organization, 1953 (Box 7, Folder 18-20)
    - Letter to Miss Karen Neuenschwander, 1959 (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - Letter to Reverend John Nickerson, 1960 (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - Northeast Arkansas Tuberculosis Association, 1960 (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - Virginia Noceti (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - Dr. Jack Novak, 1960 (Box 7, Folder 25)
    - Jack Parr, 1960 (Box 7, Folder 26)
    - Mrs. David Palaoro, 1960 (Box 7, Folder 27)
    - Rosemary Paonessa (Box 7, Folder 28)
    - Mrs. Walter Pettey, 1960 (Box 7, Folder 29)
    - Anna Marie Papriska, 1960 (Box 7, Folder 30)
    - Miscellaneous letters, P (Box 7, Folder 31)
    - Miscellaneous letters, R (Box 7, Folder 32)
    - Miscellaneous letters, S (Box 7, Folder 33)
    - Miscellaneous letters, T (Box 7, Folder 34)
    - Margaret Pele, 1960 (Box 7, Folder 35)
- Subject and Program Files, 1953-1963; III.
  This series contains information on various organizations, events, and individuals related to PARC. The folders are arranged alphabetically.
  - Allegheny County Health Department, 1956-1960 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - "Allegheny Story" copy of layout sheet (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Board of Mental Health Service, 1959-1960 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Book Reviews (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Brashear Association, 1957-1960 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Charts (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - College Funds Incorporated, 1962 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Community Advisory Council, 1956-1960 (Box 8, Folder 8-9)
  - Community Chest, 1957-1959 (Box 8, Folder 10-13)
  - Contributions, 1963 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Council of Churches, 1957-1961 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Council of Rehabilitation Agencies, 1960-1961 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - County Fair, 1957-1961 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - County Health Fair, 1959 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - County Health Offices (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Diagnostic Clinic, 1960-1962 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Directory of Services, 1960-1962 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Elections: December, 1959 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Estate of Edith L. Trees, 1960 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Fact Sheet - Speaker's Bureau Return Cards, 1960-1961 (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Family Children's Service, 1957-1959 (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Goodwill Industries, 1958-1959 (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Institutions - Private Schools, 1953-1954 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Health Fair, 1959 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Laurelton State Village, 1960 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Lawrenceville, 1962 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - League of Emotionally Disturbed Children, 1957-1959 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Legislative Material: Governor's Budget, for Public Welfare and Correction, 1959-1960 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - List of Newspapers, 1959 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Memo: East Pittsburgh Opportunity Center for Mentally Retarded Adults, July, 1962 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Memory Book, 1955-1958 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Mental Retardation Forum, 1961 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Music Institute, 1961 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - National Council of Jewish Women, 1960 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - National Foundation for Neuromuscular Disease, Inc., 1960 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Parker Publishing Co., Inc., 1959 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Pattan Trainable School, 1960 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Penn-Harris Hotel, 1960 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Penn-Sheraton Hotel, 1960 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Pennsylvania Citizen's Association, 1959-1961 (Box 9, Folder 18-19)
  - Pennsylvania Mental Health, 1960 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Pennsylvania Welfare Forum, 1960 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Dr. Richard O. Peterson, 1959 (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Pennsylvania, State of, 1960-1961 (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Photographs, 1960 (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Pittsburgh Chamber of Commerce, 1960 (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Pittsburgh, City of, 1960 (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - Pittsburgh Convention Bureau, Inc., 1960 (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - Pittsburgh Hearing Society, 1960 (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - Pittsburgh Post-Gazette, 1960-1961 (Box 9, Folder 29-30)
  - Pittsburgh Press, 1960 (Box 9, Folder 31)
  - Pittsburgh Psychological Association, 1960 (Box 9, Folder 32)
  - Pittsburgh Public Schools, 1955-1962 (Box 9, Folder 33)
  - P.K.U., 1961 (Box 9, Folder 34)
  - Police, 1960 (Box 9, Folder 35)
  - Polk Volunteer Program, 1957-1958 (Box 9, Folder 36)
  - Polk Consultation Service, 1957-1958 (Box 9, Folder 37)
  - Post-Gazette Telephone Solicitation, 1960, 1963 (Box 9, Folder 38-39)
  - President's Panel on Mental Retardation, April, 1963 (Box 9, Folder 40)
  - Program, 1958-1960 (Box 9, Folder 41-42)
  - Program (Speakers, etc), 1953-1954 (Box 9, Folder 43)
  - Project Income, 1963 (Box 9, Folder 44)
  - Property - Monroeville, 1953 (Box 9, Folder 45)
  - Public Relations, 1953-1954 (Box 9, Folder 46)
  - Recreation (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Recreation Institute - Western Pa., 1959 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Religious Education, 1957-1960 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Research, 1959 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Resolution Concerning Discrimination, 1964 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Salvation Army, 1960 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Scouts, Girl, Boy, 1956-1957 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Speaker's Bureau, 1961 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Transportation for Handicap (School laws of Pennsylvania Section 1374), 1962 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - "U" Correspondence, 1959-1960 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - United Commercial Traveler, 1960 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - University of Pittsburgh, 1958-1960 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Community Chest, United Fund, 1958-1959 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - United Fund, 1957 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - United Fund, 1956 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - United Mental Health, 1961-1963 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - "Using Community Resources to Help the Homebound or Very Retarded Child", 1958 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - "V" Correspondence, 1960 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Vocation Bible School> (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Visiting Nurses Association, 1958 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Vocational Opportunity Center, 1960-1962 (Box 10, Folder 21-23)
  - Volunteers, 1959-1961 (Box 10, Folder 24-25)
  - Volunteer Forms and Letters (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - Volunteer Projects (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - "W" Correspondence, 1960 (Box 10, Folder 28)
  - Why ACC-PARC in no longer a participant in United Fund (Box 10, Folder 29)
  - Western Diagnostic and Evaluation Center, 1958-1960 (Box 10, Folder 30)
  - "XYZ" Correspondence, 1960 (Box 10, Folder 31)
- Committees, 1953-1963; IV.
  This series contains the records of PARC committees, which is mainly in the form of minutes and correspondence. The committees were created to administer the various facets of PARC such as: education, fundraising, membership, social events, and recreation.
  - Guide for Committee Chairman (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Committee Meetings (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Bicentennial Subcommittee, 1959 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Education Committee, 1957-1961 (Box 11, Folder 4-5)
  - Finance Committee, 1953-1959 (Box 11, Folder 6-9)
  - Fundraising Committee, 1956 (Box 11, Folder 10-11)
  - Governor's Committee on Handicapped Children, 1960 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Institution Committee Minutes, 1957-1962 (Box 11, Folder 13-18)
  - Legal and Legislative Committee, 1953-1955 (Box 11, Folder 19-20)
  - Legislative Committee (Box 12, Folder 1-6)
  - Membership Committee, 1953-1955 (Box 12, Folder 7-8)
  - Membership Committee (Box 12, Folder 9-18)
  - Music Committee, 1961 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Nominating Committee, 1959-1960 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Personnel Committee, 1959-1962 (Box 13, Folder 3-4)
  - Projects Committee (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Program Committee, Correspondence, 1962-1963 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Publicity Committee, 1953-1954 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Recreation Committee (Box 13, Folder 8-13)
  - Sheltered Workshop Committee, 1958-1959 (Box 13, Folder 14-17)
  - Social Committee, 1954-1961 (Box 13, Folder 18-21)
  - Soho Class Committee (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - Soho Class Committee - Minutes, 1961 (Box 13, Folder 23)
  - Speakers Committee, 1953-1954 (Box 13, Folder 24)
  - Scope (Box 13, Folder 25)
  - Scope - Minutes, 1960 (Box 13, Folder 26)
  - Telephone Committee (Box 14, Folder 1-3)
  - TV Subcommittee - Education Committee, 1959 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Ways and Means Committee, 1961 (Box 14, Folder 5-6)
- Employment and Membership, 1959-1963; V.
  This series contains employment and membership records for the Allegheny County Chapter of PARC.
  - Members, 1960 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Memberships, 1961 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - New Members, 1961 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Memberships, 1962 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Membership Lists, 1959-1963 (Box 14, Folder 11-12)
  - Membership and Addressograph Cancellations (Box 14, Folder 13)
- Publicity, 1956-1963; VI.
  The records in this series relate to PARC's publicity campaign, which was carried out with news briefs, releases, publications, and public relations information.
  - News Briefs, 1962-1963 (Box 15, Folder 1-2)
  - Pennsylvania Association for Retarded Children Briefs (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Publicity and Public Relations, News Releases (Box 15, Folder 4-5)
  - Publicity and Public Relations, Speakers Bureau, 1956-1959 (Box 15, Folder 6-8)
  - Speakers Bureau Letters and Request Cards, 1963 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Newsletter File (Box 15, Folder 10-13)
  - Mailing Lists - Newsletter (Box 15, Folder 14)
- Social Events, 1958-1963; VII.
  The information in this series consists of social events hosted by PARC. These events were usually hosted as family outings.
  - Christmas Party, 1962-1963 (Box 16, Folder 1-2)
  - Easter Egg Hunt Reservations (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Easter Egg Hunt, 1963 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Installation Dinner, 1958-1960 (Box 16, Folder 5-10)
  - Annual Dinner (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Special Events (Box 16, Folder 12-13)
  - Summer Festival - Crafton - Ingram Shopping Center, 1962 (Box 16, Folder 14)
- Conventions, 1956-1960; VIII.
  The folders in this series consist of information about annual conventions hosted by PARC.
  - 6th Annual Convention, 1956 (Box 17, Folder 1-2)
  - 7th Annual Convention, Penn Sheraton Hotel, Pgh., May 24-25, 1957 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Annual Conventions, 1959-1960 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Conferences, 1959-1960 (Box 17, Folder 5)
- Fundraising, 1953-1961; IX.
  This series includes data on the fundraising carried out by the Allegheny County Chapter of PARC.
  - Fund Raising Campaign, 1961 (Box 18, Folder 1-4)
  - Fund Drive, 1960-1961 (Box 18, Folder 5-12)
  - Campaign Reports, 1953 (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - Telephone Recruiter Letter, 1962 (Box 18, Folder 14)
- Programs, 1953-1963; X.
  This section holds information on programs sponsored by PARC, Allegheny Chapter. The Health and Welfare Association worked in connection with the chapter on studies concerning physical rehabilitation of the mentally retarded. Friends of the Mentally Retarded was the name of PARC when it was first started. These folders hold information on the early stages of the organization.
  - Health and Welfare Association, 1957-1960 (Box 19, Folder 1-8)
  - Health and Research and Services Foundation (Box 19, Folder 9-10)
  - Friends of the Mentally Retarded, (FMR) Constitution and By-laws (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Friends of the Mentally Retarded, Executive board meeting and proposed agenda September, 1955 (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - Friends of the Mentally Retarded, Progress report, 1954-1955 (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - Friends of the Mentally Retarded, Correspondence, 1954-1956 (Box 19, Folder 14-15)
  - Friends of the Mentally Retarded, Library Records (Box 19, Folder 16)
  - Library records, Library Accession List (Box 19, Folder 17)
  - Library Materials, miscellaneous (Box 19, Folder 18)
  - Library records, Correspondence, 1954-1955 (Box 19, Folder 19-21)
  - Literature ordered (Box 19, Folder 22)
  - Administrative Policies for the Sheltered Workshop Program, 1962 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Sheltered Workshop, Minutes, 1961-1962 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Sheltered Workshop, Statement of Plans (Box 20, Folder 3-4)
  - Sheltered Workshop, Correspondence, 1957-1959 (Box 20, Folder 5-10)
  - Camp O'Connell, 1958-1959 (Box 20, Folder 11-17)
  - Camps in Pennsylvania (Box 21, Folder 1-2)
  - Camping (Box 21, Folder 3-4)
  - Camp Lillian Taylor (Box 21, Folder 5-6)
  - Campership Requests; Lillian Taylor (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Camperships Received, 1963 (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Camperships: Appeals to Clubs, 1963 (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Campership, 1963 (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - Camp Brashear (Box 21, Folder 11-13)
  - Soho Class (Box 22, Folder 1-5)
  - Soho Building (Box 22, Folder 6-7)
  - Soho Daily Progress Reports (Box 22, Folder 8-9)
  - Boy's Industrial Home - Oakdale (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Day Care Centers, 1960 (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Demonstration - Music Theory (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Edensburgh State School (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Hamburg State School - Bus Trips (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Hamburg State School (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Harmarville Rehabilitation Center (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - North Hills Pre-School (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Opportunity Center Policies and General Information, 1962 (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - Opportunity Store, 1961-1963 (Box 23, Folder 10-12)
  - Orchard School (Box 23, Folder 13)
  - Palm Beach County Association for Retarded Children, 1960 (Box 23, Folder 14)
  - Pre-school, 1962-1963 (Box 23, Folder 15)
  - Public and Parochial Schools, 1953-1955 (Box 23, Folder 16-17)
  - South Hills Class (Box 23, Folder 18)
  - At. Anthony's School (Box 23, Folder 19)
  - Wilkinsburg Pre-School Class (Box 23, Folder 20-22)
  - Woods School (Box 23, Folder 23)
  - Workshop Wages, 1962 (Box 23, Folder 24)
  - Workshop - "New Horizons in Mental Health Retardation" (Box 23, Folder 25-27)
  - Polk State School, Correspondence, 1957-1963 (Box 24, Folder 1-2)
  - Polk State School, Bus Trips (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Polk State School, Bus Schedule and Memorandum, 1963 (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Consultation Service - FMR and Polk, 1955-1956 (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Polk State School (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Family Counselor, 1960-1963 (Box 25, Folder 1-4)
  - End of School Letter, 1962 (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Nurse's Institute, 1958 (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Nurses (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Parent Education (Box 25, Folder 8-9)
  - Parent Counseling File (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - Schools (Box 25, Folder 11-14)
  - Schools in Pennsylvania (Box 25, Folder 15)
  - Schools - Description (Box 25, Folder 16)
  - Social, 1953-1954 (Box 25, Folder 17)
  - Socializing Classes (Box 25, Folder 18)
  - Training and Education Projects, 1953-1955 (Box 25, Folder 19-20)
  - Trainable (Box 25, Folder 21)
  - Teachers (Box 25, Folder 22-23)
- Scholarships and Awards, 1955-1956; XI.